Hayes Crowley - Full Stack Engineer

hayescrowley@gmail.com � Atlanta, GA

http://hayescrowley.com • https://github.com/Froglegg • https://www.linkedin.com/in/hayes-crowley/

SUMMARY

Experienced full-stack engineer and lifelong learner with a firm grasp on the latest tools and technologies for developing and driving a successful digital product. I've developed web sites and applications for Enterprise-scale companies as well as smaller NGO's as a full-time employee and contractor.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Highly skilled in React.js and MERN (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node) development, JavaScript ES6, MySQL, Postgres, Angular, Python, RESTful API development, and HTML/CSS. Experienced with several applications including VS Code, iTerm, TFS, Git, Postman and PhotoShop. Familiar with object-oriented programming (OOP) fundamentals, Agile software development, MVC Architecture, Java, PHP, WordPress, Drupal, Contentful, headless CMS, and Sitefinity.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Assurant Sept. 2018 – Present

Frontend Engineer

Atlanta, GA

• Built out frontend of 23 enterprise websites in Agile digital product team; building campaign page UI based on mockups; daily UI (CSS, JS and Bootstrap) tweaks; Node.js API (TrustPilot, Sprinklr) development; Automated repetitive tasks with Python; Sharepoint site development and CMS technical documentation; assist with releases and participate in end-of-sprint code reviews; provide technical support for content editors.

CARE USA Jan. 2017 – Sept. 2018

Web developer

Atlanta, GA

Built several micro-sites, configured API middleware and headless CMS, and built functional UI to spec. Built
out and managed content in Drupal and Wordpress. Wrote technical documentation and assisted with
content strategy.

WHISTLE PIG LLC Aug. 2016 – Present

Web Developer

Atlanta, GA

 Freelance LLC. Past clients include CARE Switzerland, Center for community Transitions, AfriCare, African Entrepreneur Collective

PROJECTS

I am always working on something new! View my Github or see my full portfolio @ http://hayescrowley.com/portfolio

EDUCATION

Georgia Tech Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

Nov. 2019

Full stack, 24-week intensive coding boot camp focusing on React.JS / Node.js / MySQL / MongoDB (MERN) development, as well as an introduction to Java and OOP fundamentals. Other learnings include version control (git), CI/CD techniques and tools (e.g. Travis), Test driven development (using Node.js Mocha/Chai), MVC architecture, DRY programming and modularity.